Hello, my name is
...nature and I'm a program manager in the windows networking team.
With this presentation I'm going to take you through the new features and updates in vp
n for windows...month-to-month we all
...news inputs of network security attacks some of us may have and even targeted
by them why this is trojan horses mal where ransom
where hacking...terms that are fast becoming commonplace in our everyday language.
In this environment is imperative to protect and secure enterprise network axis.
On the other hand
we also live in a world which is fast-paced with a few seconds delay
in access to information can be the difference between making are losing millions.
Compounding the problem of enterprises is that
they no longer are the decision takers of appreciating devices and
have even less control on how users may be using these devices?
In this new and...landscape the wavy
allow remote access needs to be modernized.
And, windows stand...are doing just that this presentation will resonate most with
...iso is network admin looking at modernizing
the remote access solution and adding new device
classes like windows phones are just starting from scratch it also
resonate with isv looking at adding to the vp and solution portfolio and our current
partners looking at modernizing their windows eight-point one solution.
In the relatively short time that people have been talking about the consumer ionization
of id the trend has generated its fair share of stories.
In the idea admin world who hasn't had a exec walk into the room and say
that I must support this new device and I want to access all the internal id websites
This generally sense quiver is down
the spine of any id admin because they need to look into the device and see how it functions.
But, in this new world that we're living in is very important that
enterprises allow access from any device
remotely.
They want to also protect access to corporate resources they want easy management
and deployment and they want to be able to audit usage and protect against data leak.
The uses on the other hand want something different they
want technology disappear they want more intuitive
...like biometric like either
scan face recognition yet they also want to be secure because they don't want to be
the ones causing losses to the company.
Taking all of this into account in windows stand...remote access and vp
and as a combination of three areas it is the mobile device management for
easy deployment and value-free maintenance.
The network access control to provide that security that the id admins one.
As well as the secure done over the internet from any device
class.
Before we go for the do let's look at what we did in windows eight-point one and how we are building on
to that story?
In windows eight-point one-b delivered...inbox weepy and solution for windows
phone this enabled...we do and ltwo dbase bbn connections why
...we also started a project called the plug-in pat platform for windows,
windows phone...this platform the isv could write a simple
weepy and solution using the windows
...api is and get full access to the
vp and technology we also added limited mgm deployment support which was
...for windows phone and...my for bc and lastly you started
and sly started on-demand vp ny app triggering but only for non domain join
machines this was a vone solution we received a lot of customer feedback.
The main feedback was around for a plug-in platform the only support
...set of partners we received a large number of requests
...isv to get access and view unable to give them access in the eight-point one solution.
We had a different deployment solution for phone and pc.
Whereas the phone use and mgm based approach the pc used
rw my based approach in addition the solutions on the phone
what delivered by the store why'd on the pc...inbox.
We also light black some of the more network security features like
per app bbn.
Ability to control the traffic going over the bbn and auditing the traffic.
Finally they will also some missing feature on the connection experience
like the always on experience...biometric...support.
Windows
...moving this story forward we really moving the needle on how we want to present remote
...solution moving forward.
You have a converge platform across desktop and
phone the advantages of that is that you see the same thing on the phone...you see on the
pc this theme language the same...same solution the same features
...also updating...plug-in platform.
...open to all-new isv.
They need to just write a you ap app that is one app for support across phone and
And,...be a uniform store base distribution so they would just be able to distribute the phone and
bc solution...store.
We also added some new security inconvenience feature that we will talk about and we
have one deployment story for both desktop and phone...fully converged.
Let's first talk about...to connect features the introducing
in windows than the always on feature.
With always on once configured vp ended always connected to the
user manually disconnects.
This gives the direct access
like convenience of your user logging into the machine and automatically connecting to
...of bbn...integrations that we'll talk about in the few in the coming slide
...for work we can make this completely seamless with the user logging in
wyatt passport for credential and getting on the vp and without any other
...we have optimize always on for our and performance it requires
no need for any of the third-party vp and solution providers to change
is completed deployable...the mgm route.
...from windows eight-point one-bit adding some more features the app triggered vp n.
Attribute vp and will now be available for domain
...machines it'll continue to support both
...pc but now why a single?
The deployment story why the mgm you can specify the file
...and the fully qualified binary name for the desktop apps
while for the store apps you need to specify the luggage but the plug-in package family name the
active profile will be used to determine which profile to trigger we'll talk about the active
...the next slide the next step is to select an active profile.
The user can choose which
profiles active using a check box as shown on the slide.
By default the
last push mgm profile will be selected as the active profile for both always...
These...auto connect features we will now move to a
features for securing the network access these...security controls
and knobs to allow the id admin to get the policy just right.
The first feature that we introducing here traffic filters.
...has been a lot of buzz about burlap vp
...in the industry but v wanted to take a slightly larger look
...to it we want to admin to be able to determine
what goes over the vp and what doesn't based on application
characteristics as well as just a traffic characters characteristics and we're going to do...
The first step of characteristics among them but, app bbn.
This controls the apps that allowed over the bbn you can have either
...or split paradigms at the
...layer themselves what that means is that if you select split you saying that you
trust this app is allowed to go with
the vp and interface but it can also go over the internet with forced on
...us saying that this app is required from my vp
and interface but should not go over the internet if
vp and disconnected this again works with the eight-point one bbn
plugins without any modifications now.
You can also specified traffic rules on the traffic characteristics you can specify based on the
local remote port ranges local remote ip ranges the protocol
...st dl base claim within each ruin each by the media is
...evaluated within and operation
and across multiple rules that evaluated based on or.
You can...based rules as well as device wide rules this allows you to
...the policy just as you deem fit another entrant to a portfolio is the
...bbn this is for the extremely security-conscious organization
typically seen as government organisations are defense contractors or any organization that
needs to be paranoid about...vp and access.
Once deployed all ip traffic will go only over the
vp and interface vp and will always be connected the user will not be able to
disconnect connection and user will not be able to modify this connection if the vp
and interfaces not present all ip traffic will be...
see this as being used on business devices which are used only for business purposes.
The next set of feature that I'm going to talk about...more integration with the general windows
...philosophy the first among them is passport forward and the vp and
...experience.
With windows...passport for work is integrated with bbn.
This means that you can use strong to fact authentication
...to the ease of use which means you could use your
iris authentication face recognition biometric all for vp
...as well in addition...also integrated to the
login screen that means that once you log in with your windows hello credential the passport for work
credential taken the kicking the back and
...connected automatically if you have always on deployed this gives a
newly based authentication along with a strong fact authentication for
...another integration point for we pied is
the enterprise data protection another thing that you will...of in multiple other
presentation that build enterprise data protection helps to both.
Protect data addressed as well as on the move.
This is a different approach from others in the industry because we're actually going to detect data
as personal enterprise and only protect enterprise data allowing this to be used for by
...devices with the enterprise data protection rules at the data egress
will be able to use the policy to
determine if the data enterprise are not and only allow the enterprise data to go with the vp
and interface will also...the vp
and interface automatically based on whether the enterprise data is allowed or not.
The next slides talk about the deployment option...understand are promise
...customer is that bbn is going to be easy to deploy an easy to maintain.
With that in our minds we went with
the fully convert mgm solution which had to be redesign from scratch.
The reason from redesigning was he wanted to go back and, look, at the feedback from both...enterprises and work on
that this esp is going to be the same across for nbc allowing you
one deployment story altogether it supports all the new windows
...features and ecm can even leverage the...esp bridge to deploy ys
For backwards compatibility we still have...the all the pnc sp on the phone but
we do recommend new implementations to be based on this new...
Another new approach that we've gone with is allowing store app
...deployment this means that isv now access
to api is allowing them to build their own custom solutions this will allow them
to create edit modify connect...connection to the api is.
The mainline scenarios that we're thinking here a
...app...app is typically something that...enterprise would
write and the right that so that they can give this one-click solution to
...enterprise uses they open the app click a button
...connected in the background and they get a whole list of links that they can basically access over
...vp and interface the next start is
a holistic vp and solution for plug-in providers with their branding.
Vp and solution vendors already have an application on the store.
And, that provides...functionality they can marry that with these api is
...actually provide a full end-to-end experience
...application itself the code in this
...scenarios is consumer bbn.
Consumer vp is a fast growing segment.
Where mobile network operators and security isv
I'll building that own vp...solution to basically allow
protection of consumer devices data by allowing this data to go over the vp
...tunnel and on the server and the
do some analysis and the traffic before letting it go out this is a fast growing industry and something
that we very supportive off the next slides talk about updates to the
...want to help the isv deliver innovative remote access solutions
with windows then we cs cells not only an inbox solution provider
back-up partner...a platform to allow isv to...
We are now open to all isv.
...will have public documentation guiding them through on how to become a vp
and isv and in the in datum if you contact
...customer account team we would be happy to help...as well.
The...and api is fully converge across for nbc and as I mentioned earlier you just need to
...one...application for both phone
nbc there will be avce they'll get capability guarding the axes the
...is but are documentation guide you through that as well.
What additional topic on this is the windows eight-point one
upgrades story why this is an issue is that in windows eight-point one for of
...partners...actually shipped
in-box and we're going to be moving them across to the store?
...to support the...story from here such that once...user
...windows eight-point want to windows ten and they have a profile with the old...all
in-box client they will be able to migrate to the store and will
have will be able to preserve the vp and settings?
For new isv as I mentioned the program will be
...they'll be able to create
...the vp and plug-in as well as of axes the connection manager api is.
The new a new processor...made public on msdn and there will be a capability gating the
...the api is which we will give to any
...that we talked to and deemed to have a solution requiring bbn.
That covers...updates for windows stand the bn now you move over
to do a demo I'm going to demo here per app bbn as well as
app triggering to show you how you can
...policy for secure network remote access.
So, with this demo I'm going to show you a glimpse of the per app vp...with app
...in this setup currently if you go if I
...show you there is no vp and connection initially.
I'll go ahead and deploy this db and
solution currently why a command-line script which we basically...
...the rule that internet explorer should automatically trigger to the vp
and connection deployed and should be the only one that
...is allowed to go over the vp and interface?
Deploy I will just go ahead and run this to present administrator.
And, you will see that the...and connection is now shown over here.
This we been connection is not currently connected.
If I now to trigger spartan.
The vp and connection is still not going to be connected because the spartan browser
is not the in the as the policy is not the app that...bbn.
As soon...open ie do what
...the background is...connection is triggered and when I go and check?
If we show that the vp and actually connected now if I try to go to an internal website.
I will see that I can successfully go-to it but when I try the same with the spartan browser.
It will be unable to do so.
Now just to show that this is basically based on policy I'm going to...the vp
And, show you that if it is on the corporate environment spartan could have actually reach
that a particular website.
Now note for the purpose...a...demo my internet interface is on
my corporate network which is why without...vp and I can reach the
cognate these...still applied over this because
...been interfaces becomes preferred interface.
And, here you see it that and nowthe ...actually open by
a spartan while the vp and is still not connected and that was my demo on per
app vp and app triggering if
you around for build and ignite you should check out the sessions as well?
Thank you
that concludes my talk on securing the enterprise access and vp and for windows...